<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><document><metadata><meta name="title">Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae).</meta><meta name="snippet">See comment in PubMed Commons below</meta><meta name="abstract">Tamgermanitin, a unique N-trans-Isoferuloyltyramine, together with the hitherto unknown polyphenolics, 2,4-di-O-galloyl-(α/β)-glucopyranose and kaempferide 3,7-disulphate have been isolated from the leaf aqueous ethanol extract of the false tamarisk, Myricaria germanica DESV. In addition, 18 known phenolics were also separated and characterized. All structures were elucidated on the basis of detailed analysis of 1D- (1)H and (13)C NMR, COSY, HSQC, HMBC and HRFTESIMS spectral data. The extract, its chromatographic column fractions and the isolated isoferuloyltyramine, tamgermanetin demonstrated potential cytotoxic effect against three different tumor cell lines, namely liver (Huh-7), breast (MCF-7) and prostate (PC-3). The IC 50''s were found to be substantially low with low-resistance possibility. DNA flow-cytometic analysis indicated that column fractions and tamgermanetin enhanced pre-G apoptotic fraction. Both materials showed inhibiting activity against PARP enzyme activity. In conclusion, we report the isolation and identification of a novel compound, tamgermanitin, from the aqueous ethanol extract of Myricaria germanica leaves. Further, different fractions of the extract and tamgermanitin exhibit potent cytotoxic activities which warrant further investigations.</meta><meta name="objective"/><meta name="methods"/><meta name="results"/><meta name="conclusions"/><meta name="id">23123452;</meta><meta name="authors">Nawwar MA</meta><meta name="source">Plant signaling &amp; behavior.</meta><meta name="pubdate">2012/11/6</meta><meta name="keywords">2,4-di-O-galloyl-(α/β)-glucopyranose</meta><meta name="keywords">Myricaria germanica</meta><meta name="keywords">N-trans-Isoferuloyltyramine</meta><meta name="keywords">cytotoxicity</meta><meta name="keywords">kaempferide 3,7-disulphate</meta><meta name="keywords">tamgermanitin</meta></metadata><content>
    	
			
				
					
    
    
	
	Warning:
	The NCBI web site requires JavaScript to function. 
	more...
	
	
    
    NCBISkip to main
                        contentSkip to
                        navigationResourcesAll ResourcesChemicals &amp; BioassaysBioSystemsPubChem BioAssayPubChem CompoundPubChem Structure SearchPubChem SubstanceAll Chemicals &amp; Bioassays Resources...DNA &amp; RNABLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool)BLAST (Stand-alone)E-UtilitiesGenBankGenBank: BankItGenBank: SequinGenBank: tbl2asnGenome WorkbenchInfluenza VirusNucleotide DatabasePopSetPrimer-BLASTProSplignReference Sequence (RefSeq)RefSeqGeneSequence Read Archive (SRA)SplignTrace ArchiveUniGeneAll DNA &amp; RNA Resources...Data &amp; SoftwareBLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool)BLAST (Stand-alone)Cn3DConserved Domain Search Service (CD Search)E-UtilitiesGenBank: BankItGenBank: SequinGenBank: tbl2asnGenome ProtMapGenome WorkbenchPrimer-BLASTProSplignPubChem Structure SearchSNP Submission ToolSplignVector Alignment Search Tool (VAST)All Data &amp; Software Resources...Domains &amp; StructuresBioSystemsCn3DConserved Domain Database (CDD)Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search)Structure (Molecular Modeling Database)Vector Alignment Search Tool (VAST)All Domains &amp; Structures Resources...Genes &amp; ExpressionBioSystemsDatabase of Genotypes and Phenotypes (dbGaP)E-UtilitiesGeneGene Expression Omnibus (GEO) Database Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) DatasetsGene Expression Omnibus (GEO) ProfilesGenome WorkbenchHomoloGeneMap ViewerOnline Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM)RefSeqGeneUniGeneAll Genes &amp; Expression Resources...Genetics &amp; MedicineBookshelfDatabase of Genotypes and Phenotypes (dbGaP)Genetic Testing RegistryInfluenza VirusMap ViewerOnline Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM)PubMedPubMed Central (PMC)PubMed Clinical QueriesRefSeqGeneAll Genetics &amp; Medicine Resources...Genomes &amp; MapsDatabase of Genomic Structural Variation (dbVar)GenBank: tbl2asnGenomeGenome ProjectGenome ProtMapGenome WorkbenchInfluenza VirusMap ViewerNucleotide DatabasePopSetProSplignSequence Read Archive (SRA)SplignTrace ArchiveAll Genomes &amp; Maps Resources...HomologyBLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool)BLAST (Stand-alone)BLAST Link (BLink)Conserved Domain Database (CDD)Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search)Genome ProtMapHomoloGeneProtein ClustersAll Homology Resources...LiteratureBookshelfE-UtilitiesJournals in NCBI DatabasesMeSH DatabaseNCBI HandbookNCBI Help ManualNCBI NewsPubMedPubMed Central (PMC)PubMed Clinical QueriesPubMed HealthAll Literature Resources...ProteinsBioSystemsBLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool)BLAST (Stand-alone)BLAST Link (BLink)Conserved Domain Database (CDD)Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search)E-UtilitiesProSplignProtein ClustersProtein DatabaseReference Sequence (RefSeq)All Proteins Resources...Sequence AnalysisBLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool)BLAST (Stand-alone)BLAST Link (BLink)Conserved Domain Search Service (CD Search)Genome ProtMapGenome WorkbenchInfluenza VirusPrimer-BLASTProSplignSplignAll Sequence Analysis Resources...TaxonomyTaxonomyTaxonomy BrowserTaxonomy Common TreeAll Taxonomy Resources...Training &amp; TutorialsNCBI Education PageNCBI HandbookNCBI Help ManualNCBI NewsAll Training &amp; Tutorials Resources...VariationDatabase of Genomic Structural Variation (dbVar)Database of Genotypes and Phenotypes (dbGaP)Database of Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms (dbSNP)SNP Submission ToolAll Variation Resources...How ToAll How ToChemicals &amp; BioassaysDNA &amp; RNAData &amp; SoftwareDomains &amp; StructuresGenes &amp; ExpressionGenetics &amp; MedicineGenomes &amp; MapsHomologyLiteratureProteinsSequence AnalysisTaxonomyTraining &amp; TutorialsVariationAbout NCBI AccesskeysMy NCBISign in to NCBISign Out
    
    
    
    
    PubMed
    
        US National Library of Medicine
        National Institutes of Health
    

    
    Search databaseAll DatabasesAssemblyBioProjectBioSampleBioSystemsBooksClinVarCloneConserved DomainsdbGaPdbVarEpigenomicsESTGeneGenomeGEO DataSetsGEO ProfilesGSSGTRHomoloGeneMedGenMeSHNCBI Web SiteNLM CatalogNucleotideOMIMPMCPopSetProbeProteinProtein ClustersPubChem BioAssayPubChem CompoundPubChem SubstancePubMedPubMed HealthSNPSRAStructureTaxonomyToolKitToolKitAllToolKitBookUniGeneSearch termSearchAdvancedHelp
   
    
    
    Result Filters
    


    
        AbstractFormatSummarySummary (text)AbstractAbstract (text)MEDLINEXMLPMID ListApplySend to:
                        jQuery(document).ready( function () {
                            jQuery("#send_to_menu input[type='radio']").click( function () {
                                var selectedValue = jQuery(this).val().toLowerCase();
                                var selectedDiv = jQuery("#send_to_menu div." + selectedValue);
                                
                                if(selectedDiv.is(":hidden")){ 
                                jQuery("#send_to_menu div.submenu:visible").slideUp();
                                selectedDiv.slideDown();
                                }
                            });
                        
                        });
                        
                        jQuery("#sendto").bind("ncbipopperclose", function(){
                            jQuery("#send_to_menu div.submenu:visible").css("display","none");
                            jQuery("#send_to_menu input[type='radio']:checked").attr("checked",false);
                        });
                        
                    Choose DestinationFileClipboardCollectionsE-mailOrderMy BibliographyCitation managerFormatSummary (text)Abstract (text)MEDLINEXMLPMID ListCSVCreate File1 selected item: 23123452FormatSummarySummary (text)AbstractAbstract (text)MEDLINEXMLPMID ListMeSH and Other DataE-mailSubjectAdditional textE-mailDidn't get the message? Find out why...Add to ClipboardAdd to CollectionsOrder articlesAdd to My BibliographyGenerate a file for use with external citation management software.Create File
        
    
    
    
    
    
    

        
            
            
               
        
            
            
            
            
        
        See comment in PubMed Commons belowPlant Signal Behav. 2013 Jan;8(1):e22642. doi: 10.4161/psb.22642. Epub  2012 Nov 3.Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae).Nawwar MA1, Swilam NF2, Hashim AN1, Al-Abd AM3, Abdel-Naim AB4, Lindequist U2.Author information1Department of Phytochemistry and Plant Systematic; National Research Center; Dokki, Cairo, Egypt.2Institute for Pharmacy; Pharmaceutical Biology; Ernst-Moritz-Arndt-University Greifswald; Greifswald, Germany.3Department of Pharmacology; National Research Center; Dokki, Cairo, Egypt.4Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology; Ain Shams University; Cairo, Egypt.AbstractTamgermanitin, a unique N-trans-Isoferuloyltyramine, together with the hitherto unknown polyphenolics, 2,4-di-O-galloyl-(α/β)-glucopyranose and kaempferide 3,7-disulphate have been isolated from the leaf aqueous ethanol extract of the false tamarisk, Myricaria germanica DESV. In addition, 18 known phenolics were also separated and characterized. All structures were elucidated on the basis of detailed analysis of 1D- (1)H and (13)C NMR, COSY, HSQC, HMBC and HRFTESIMS spectral data. The extract, its chromatographic column fractions and the isolated isoferuloyltyramine, tamgermanetin demonstrated potential cytotoxic effect against three different tumor cell lines, namely liver (Huh-7), breast (MCF-7) and prostate (PC-3). The IC 50''s were found to be substantially low with low-resistance possibility. DNA flow-cytometic analysis indicated that column fractions and tamgermanetin enhanced pre-G apoptotic fraction. Both materials showed inhibiting activity against PARP enzyme activity. In conclusion, we report the isolation and identification of a novel compound, tamgermanitin, from the aqueous ethanol extract of Myricaria germanica leaves. Further, different fractions of the extract and tamgermanitin exhibit potent cytotoxic activities which warrant further investigations. KEYWORDS: 2,4-di-O-galloyl-(α/β)-glucopyranose; Myricaria germanica; N-trans-Isoferuloyltyramine; cytotoxicity; kaempferide 3,7-disulphate; tamgermanitinPMID: 23123452  [PubMed - indexed for MEDLINE] PMCID: PMC3745567 Free PMC ArticleShareImages from this publication.See all images  (6)Free textFigure 4.  Compound 2. Kaempferide 3,7-disodium sulfate.Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae)Plant Signal Behav. 2013 January 1;8(1):e22642.Figure 5.  Compound 12. 2,4-di-O-(α/β) galloyl glucopyranose.Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae)Plant Signal Behav. 2013 January 1;8(1):e22642.Figure 6.  Tamgermanetin. N-trans-3-hydroxy 4-methoxy cinnamoyltyramine.Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae)Plant Signal Behav. 2013 January 1;8(1):e22642.Figure 1. Effect of tamarixellagic acid and tamgermanitin on the cell cycle distribution of Huh-7 cells. Cells were exposed to tamarixellagic acid (B) and tamgermanitin (C) for 24 h and compared with control cells (A). Cell cycle distribution was determined using DNA cytometry analysis and different cell phases were plotted (D) as percent of total events (n = 3).Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae)Plant Signal Behav. 2013 January 1;8(1):e22642.Figure 2. Effect of tamarixellagic acid and tamgermanitin on the cell cycle distribution of MCF-7 cells. Cells were exposed to tamarixellagic acid (B) and tamgermanitin (C) for 24 h and compared with control cells (A). Cell cycle distribution was determined using DNA cytometry analysis and different cell phases were plotted (D) as percent of total events (n = 3).Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae)Plant Signal Behav. 2013 January 1;8(1):e22642.Figure 3. Effect of tamarixellagic acid and tamgermanitin on PARP (A) and caspase-3 (B) enzyme activity was assessed in cell-free system and in Huh-7 cell, respectively. Data are presented as mean ± SEM; (n = 3).Cytotoxic isoferulic acidamide from Myricaria germanica (Tamaricaceae)Plant Signal Behav. 2013 January 1;8(1):e22642.Publication Types, MeSH Terms, SubstancesPublication TypesResearch Support, Non-U.S. Gov'tMeSH TermsApoptosisBreast Neoplasms/drug therapy*Cell ProliferationCoumaric Acids/chemistryCoumaric Acids/isolation &amp; purificationCoumaric Acids/pharmacologyCoumaric Acids/therapeutic use*HumansInhibitory Concentration 50Liver Neoplasms/drug therapy*MCF-7 CellsMaleMolecular StructurePhytotherapy*Plant Extracts/chemistryPlant Extracts/isolation &amp; purificationPlant Extracts/pharmacologyPlant Extracts/therapeutic use*Plant LeavesPoly(ADP-ribose) Polymerases/antagonists &amp; inhibitorsPolyphenols/chemistryPolyphenols/isolation &amp; purificationPolyphenols/pharmacologyPolyphenols/therapeutic useProstatic Neoplasms/drug therapy*Tamaricaceae/chemistry*Tyramine/analogs &amp; derivatives*Tyramine/chemistryTyramine/isolation &amp; purificationTyramine/pharmacologyTyramine/therapeutic useSubstancesCoumaric AcidsN-(3-hydroxy-4-methoxycinnamoyl)tyraminePlant ExtractsPolyphenolsPoly(ADP-ribose) PolymerasesTyramineLinkOut - more resourcesFull Text SourcesEurope PubMed CentralPubMed CentralPubMed Central CanadaOther Literature SourcesAccess more work from the authors - ResearchGateMedicalBreast Cancer - MedlinePlus Health InformationHerbal Medicine - MedlinePlus Health InformationLiver Cancer - MedlinePlus Health InformationProstate Cancer - MedlinePlus Health InformationMiscellaneousTYRAMINE - Hazardous Substances Data BankPubMed Commons home
                               PubMed Commons
                               0 commentsHow to join PubMed CommonsHow to cite this comment:
        
            
        
        
            
        
        
    
  

    Supplemental Content
      
    
    
    Full text links 
    
    

    
    
    
    
    
    


    
    
    You are here: 
            NCBI &gt; Literature &gt; PubMed
    Write to the Help Desk
    


    
    
    
        Simple NCBI Directory
        
            Getting Started
            
            NCBI Education
            NCBI Help Manual
            NCBI Handbook
            Training &amp; Tutorials
            Submit Data
        
        
        
            Resources
            
        Chemicals &amp; BioassaysData &amp; SoftwareDNA &amp; RNADomains &amp; StructuresGenes &amp; ExpressionGenetics &amp; MedicineGenomes &amp; MapsHomologyLiteratureProteinsSequence AnalysisTaxonomyVariation
        
        
            Popular
            PubMed
            Bookshelf
            PubMed Central
            PubMed Health
            BLAST            
            Nucleotide
            Genome
            SNP
            Gene
            Protein
            PubChem
        
        
            Featured
            Genetic Testing Registry
            PubMed Health
            GenBank
            Reference Sequences
            Gene Expression Omnibus
            Map Viewer
            Human Genome
            Mouse Genome
            Influenza Virus
            Primer-BLAST
            Sequence Read Archive
        
        
            NCBI Information
            About NCBI
            Research at NCBI
            NCBI News
            NCBI FTP Site
            NCBI on Facebook
            NCBI on Twitter
            NCBI on YouTube
        
    
    
        External link. Please review our privacy policy.
        
          
        
            
                NLM
            
            
                NIH
            
            
                DHHS
            
            
                USA.gov
                     
        
        
        
            
                
                    National Center for
                        Biotechnology Information,
                 U.S. National Library of Medicine
                
                    8600 Rockville Pike, Bethesda
                    MD, 20894
                    USA
                
            
            
            Policies and Guidelines | Contact
        
    
         
     



					
				
			
		
    




</content></document>